<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>religion on nukant</title>
    <link>/tags/religion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in religion on nukant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:18:58 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/religion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Angel Gabriel, John, Jesus, and Muhammad</title>
      <link>/posts/the-angel-gabriel-john-jesus-muhammad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:18:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-angel-gabriel-john-jesus-muhammad/</guid>
      <description>This post is mainly about the Angel Gabriel, and the confusion that the revelations cause in interpreting the Abrahamic faiths: Gabriel first appears to John the Baptist&amp;rsquo;s father, Zacharias, preparing Zacharias for the arrival of John, from the womb of Mary&amp;rsquo;s cousin Elisabeth
10 And the whole multitude of the people were praying without at the time of incense. 11 And there appeared unto him an angel of the Lord standing on the right side of the altar of incense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noble Eight-Fold Path</title>
      <link>/posts/noble-eight-fold-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:16:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/noble-eight-fold-path/</guid>
      <description>These are the eight noble truths in Buddhism:
Right View: our actions have consequences, death is not the end, and our actions and beliefs have consequences after death. The Buddha followed and taught a successful path out of this world and the other world (heaven and underworld/hell). Later on, right view came to explicitly include karma and rebirth, and the importance of the Four Noble Truths, when &amp;ldquo;insight&amp;rdquo; became central to Buddhist soteriology, especially in Theravada Buddhism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Noble Truths</title>
      <link>/posts/four-noble-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:14:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/four-noble-truths/</guid>
      <description>The Four Noble Truths describe the reality of the struggle with life and a way to curb strife through the curbing of craving and the following of the noble eight-fold path.
The Four Noble Truths are:
dukkha (literally &amp;ldquo;suffering&amp;rdquo;; here &amp;ldquo;unsatisfactoriness&amp;rdquo;) is an innate characteristic of existence in the realm of samsara;
samudaya (origin, arising, combination;&amp;lsquo;cause&amp;rsquo;): dukkha arises or continues with tanhā (&amp;ldquo;craving, desire or attachment, lit.&amp;ldquo;thirst&amp;rdquo;). tanhā is traditionally interpreted in western languages as the &amp;lsquo;cause&amp;rsquo; of dukkha , tanha can also be seen as the factor tying us to dukkha, or as a response to dukkha, trying to escape it;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
