<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>buddhism on nukant</title>
    <link>/tags/buddhism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in buddhism on nukant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:16:20 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/buddhism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Noble Eight-Fold Path</title>
      <link>/posts/noble-eight-fold-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:16:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/noble-eight-fold-path/</guid>
      <description>These are the eight noble truths in Buddhism:
Right View: our actions have consequences, death is not the end, and our actions and beliefs have consequences after death. The Buddha followed and taught a successful path out of this world and the other world (heaven and underworld/hell). Later on, right view came to explicitly include karma and rebirth, and the importance of the Four Noble Truths, when &amp;ldquo;insight&amp;rdquo; became central to Buddhist soteriology, especially in Theravada Buddhism.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;These are the eight noble truths in Buddhism:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right View: our actions have consequences, death is not the end, and our actions and beliefs have consequences after death. The Buddha followed and taught a successful path out of this world and the other world (heaven and underworld/hell). Later on, right view came to explicitly include karma and rebirth, and the importance of the Four Noble Truths, when &amp;ldquo;insight&amp;rdquo; became central to Buddhist soteriology, especially in Theravada Buddhism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right Resolve or Intention: the giving up of home and adopting the life of a religious mendicant in order to follow the path; this concept aims at peaceful renunciation, into an environment of non-sensuality, non-ill-will (to loving kindness), away from cruelty (to compassion). Such an environment aids contemplation of impermanence , suffering, and non-Self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right Speech: no lying, no rude speech, no telling one person what another says about him to cause discord or harm their relationship, no idle chatter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right Conduct or Action: no killing or injuring, no taking what is not given, no sexual misconduct, no material desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right Livelihood: no trading in weapons, living beings, meat, liquor, and poisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right Effort: preventing the arising of unwholesome states, and generating wholesome states, the bojjhagā ( Seven Factors of Awakening). This includes indriya-samvara ,&amp;ldquo;guarding the sense-doors&amp;rdquo;, restraint of the sense faculties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right Mindfulness (sati ; Satipatthana ; Sampajañña): a quality that guards or watches over the mind; the stronger it becomes, the weaker unwholesome states of mind become, weakening their power &amp;ldquo;to take over and dominate thought, word and deed.&amp;rdquo; In the vipassana movement , sati is interpreted as &amp;ldquo;bare attention&amp;rdquo;: never be absent minded, being conscious of what one is doing; this encourages the awareness of the impermanence of body, feeling and mind, as well as to experience the five aggregates (skandhas), the five hindrances, the four True Realities and seven factors of awakening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right samadhi ( passaddhi ; ekaggata ; sampasadana): practicing four stages of dhyāna (&amp;ldquo;meditation&amp;rdquo;), which includes samadhi proper in the second stage, and reinforces the development of the bojjhagā, culminating into upekkha (equanimity) and mindfulness. In the Theravada tradition and the vipassana movement, this is interpreted as ekaggata, concentration or one-pointedness of the mind, and supplemented with vipassana meditation, which aims at insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &amp;ldquo;Noble Eightfold Path&amp;rdquo;, wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four Noble Truths</title>
      <link>/posts/four-noble-truths/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 04:14:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/four-noble-truths/</guid>
      <description>The Four Noble Truths describe the reality of the struggle with life and a way to curb strife through the curbing of craving and the following of the noble eight-fold path.
The Four Noble Truths are:
dukkha (literally &amp;ldquo;suffering&amp;rdquo;; here &amp;ldquo;unsatisfactoriness&amp;rdquo;) is an innate characteristic of existence in the realm of samsara;
samudaya (origin, arising, combination;&amp;lsquo;cause&amp;rsquo;): dukkha arises or continues with tanhā (&amp;ldquo;craving, desire or attachment, lit.&amp;ldquo;thirst&amp;rdquo;). tanhā is traditionally interpreted in western languages as the &amp;lsquo;cause&amp;rsquo; of dukkha , tanha can also be seen as the factor tying us to dukkha, or as a response to dukkha, trying to escape it;</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;The Four Noble Truths describe the reality of the struggle with life and a way to curb strife through the curbing of craving and the following of the noble eight-fold path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Four Noble Truths are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dukkha (literally &amp;ldquo;suffering&amp;rdquo;; here &amp;ldquo;unsatisfactoriness&amp;rdquo;) is an innate characteristic of existence in the realm of samsara;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;samudaya (origin, arising, combination;&amp;lsquo;cause&amp;rsquo;): dukkha arises or continues with tanhā (&amp;ldquo;craving, desire or attachment, lit.&amp;ldquo;thirst&amp;rdquo;). tanhā is traditionally interpreted in western languages as the &amp;lsquo;cause&amp;rsquo; of dukkha , tanha can also be seen as the factor tying us to dukkha, or as a response to dukkha, trying to escape it;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nirodha (cessation, ending, confinement): dukkha can be ended or contained by the renouncement or letting go of this tanhā; the confinement of taṇhā releases the excessive bind of dukkha;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;marga (path, Noble Eightfold Path) is the path leading to the confinement of tanha and dukkha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &amp;ldquo;Four Noble Truths&amp;rdquo;, wikipedia&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
